

# CONTACT DETAILS



they/them/theirs



Brooklyn, NY



516-554-1060



leahcardoz@gmail.com



<u>Portfolio</u>



LinkedIn



Github



Blog

# TECHNICAL SKILLS

ReactJS

JavaScript

Ruby

Rails

HTML

CSS

Material UI

Semantic UI

PostgreSQL

RESTful APIs

• Git

Github

Figma

Netlify

## ABOUT ME

Full stack software engineer with a knack for eye-catching, user-friendly web design. With a decade of experience supporting C-Level executives in the live music industry, I excel in delivering optimal results with professionalism in high-pressure environments. As a proud member of the AAPI and LGBTQ+ communities eager to begin my career in tech, I look forward to expanding my skill set at a workplace that values integrity and embraces community.

## TECHNICAL PROJECTS

### GIG PRINTS - GITHUB | DEMO

A hub for bands and poster designers to connect and create concert posters together

- Utilized React and Rails to facilitate and harness CRUD actions for three models.
- Implemented authentication and authorization using encryption and user sessions.
- Incorporated react-router client-side routes and uniform styling with Semantic UI.
- Compiled API from scratch leveraging foreign keys for the joiner poster model.

### ENGINE-EAR. - GITHUB | DEMO

A social media app solely for software engineers to interact, network, and post content

- Integrated a user-friendly React interface with a Ruby Rails authenticated backend.
- Utilized six models via ActiveRecord including a self join table with user alias ids.
- Strengthened signup and login security with hashing, salting, and bcrypt.
- Created a feature to filter content by tags such as job postings, projects, and blogs.

### THE ARCHIVE - GITHUB (FRONTEND) | GITHUB (BACKEND) | DEMO

An app where users can showcase & submit their favorite screenprint artists and prints

- Built frontend with React and backend with Ruby Sinatra to demonstrate full CRUD.
- Engineered RESTful Routing by leveraging ActiveRecord associations for methods.
- Elevated frontend styling with CSS including hover-over effects and timed slideshow.

# EDUCATION

#### **FLATIRON SCHOOL**

Software Engineering Program
OCT 2022 - JAN 2023

### UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA, BERKELEY - WALTER A. HAAS SCHOOL OF BUSINESS

B.A. Business Administration AUG 2011 – MAY 2015

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### **EXECUTIVE ASSISTANT TO CEO/FOUNDER**

MAY 2021 - SEPT 2022

City Winery International - New York, NY

- Efficiently streamlined CEO's workflow by organizing schedules and owning projects.
- Advanced company's growth by conducting market research for new locations.
- Independently spearheaded large events, such as management off-site conferences.

### ARTIST AGENT ASSISTANT

JUNE 2015 - JULY 2018

High Road Touring - Sausalito, CA

- Convened with CEO and agents to efficiently book concert tours for 300+ artists.
- Supervised the Contracts & Wages Departments, assuring correct earnings for artists.
- Managed the Admin Department by scheduling meetings and training all new hires.